Guide to the Frank Cheyne Papé Letters and drawings, ca. 1921-1931
Department of Special Collections
- FRANK PAPÉ ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the NORMAN H. STROUSE COLLECTION From RABELAIS (Box 4)
  - RABELAIS - Volume II - Original Pape Drawings in Strouse Collection (Box 4)
    - Rabelais pointing to open book (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
      TOTAL 55 original drawings. The detailed description of the drawings, their frequent repetition, and the separate appearance of the many parts, therefore does not tally with the actual count of the original drawings.
- FRANK PAPÉ ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the NORMAN H. STROUSE Collection from AT THE SIGH OF THE REINE PEDAUQUE (Box 5)
  - FRANCE, Anatole. At The Sign of the Reine Pedauque. Translated by Mrs. Wilfred Jackson with Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Papé and an Introduction by William J. Lacke. 8vo. 1st illustrated edition. With double page decorated endleaves, front and back, 12 full page illustrations, 1 decorated half-title, 1 heading, 21 tail-pieces, and 30 decorated initiale. Black cloth binding, gilt-stamped with Pape designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. (1922)
    Copy 2 - exactly alike but is 1923 reprint with original dust-jacket, decorated in red with Papé designs. PRESENTATION COPY to Walter M. Hill, with original pen drawing tipped in preceding half-title.
    - 2 customers at table, Double full page
    - Illus. and letterpress, Full page (missing drawing)
    - I will go..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - A Salamander..., Full page
    - It is their only patron..., Full page
    - This gentleman..., Full page
    - The shape of this box..., Full page
    - I recognised..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - You are my Salamander..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Hysurprise - Croignard, Full page (drawing missing)
    - During his slumber..., Full page
    - For whom the angels..., Full page
    - I arise on wings..., Full page
    - Such was their lot..., Full page
    - Father dandling baby, Heading to Chapter I -3/4 p.
    - Decorated initials 30 -- 1 x 3/4"
      (no original initial drawings in collection. These were not included with any of the original drawings)
    - 2 goblets, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Father Coignard, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Cupid, arrow and heart, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - veiled door knocker, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - 3 guests at table, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - 2 hearts, lady and gentleman, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Scales, lady and owl, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - Gentleman passes window, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Men shaking hands on stair, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Medallion, Mosaide brooding, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - dog, coach, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Row of naked Salamanders, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Tournebroche refused house, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Jael kissing Tournebroche, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Abbe following Tournebroche, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jael escaping window, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Hosaide, medallion, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Bunches of grapes, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Cross, chalice, grapes, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Cross, chalice, grapes, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Salamanders carry d'Asterac away, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Finis, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
      Total
      4 original drawings for endleaves
      1 original drawings for hoading
      7 drawings for full page illustrations (4 missing)
      20 drawings for tailpieces (1 missing)
      32 original drawings for La Reine Pedauque in Strouse Collection
      no half title drawing in collection
      none of the 30 initial drawings in collection - but this was usual.
      TOTAL 33 original drawings. The detailed description of the drawings, their frequent repetition, and the separation of the many parts, therefore does not tall with the actual count of the original drawings.
- FRANK PAPE ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the Norman H. STROUSE COLLECTION From THE REVOLT OF THE ANGELS (Box 6)
  - FRANCE, Anatole. The Revolt of the Angels. Translated by Mrs. Wilfred Jackson with Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Pape. 8vo. 1st illus. sdeition. With 12 full page illustrations, double page decorated endpapers at front and back, 1 heading, 28 el boratoly decorated tailpieces, decorated halftitle, and 30 decorated initials. Black cloth binding, gilt-stamped with Pape designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. c.1924
    Copy 2. Same as Copy 1 except for American publisher's imprint (Dodd, Head) in gold on backstrip.
    - Cannons besieging castle, Double full page
    - Triumphant angels, spears, Half-title - 3/4 p. (drawing missing)
    - Bust and flags, Heading - ¼ p.
    - Dies Irae..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Hons. Sarriette fell..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - The following night..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - I Was commanded..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - In Paradise..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Such was Istar..., Full page
    - I sang to..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Pestilence and famine, Full page (drawing missing)
    - Prince Istar..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Gilberto decided..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - To sound of bells..., Full page (drawing missing)
    - Areado, Istar, and Zite, Full page (drawing missing)
      Only one full page illustration - original drawing - in collection, Istar opposite page 118 - others (10) missing. The word missing refers only original drawings. All illustrations in books themselves, are intact. No decorated initials for any of the Pape editions are included in the original drawings of the collection.
      TOTAL 22 original drawings. The detailed description of the drawings, their frequent repetitions, and the separation of any parts, therefore does not tally with the actual count of the original drawings.
    - angel, man and out, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - dejected monkey, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - leoping leopard, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - angels with flame, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - medallion, donkey reading, Tailpiece - ¼ p. (drawing missing)
    - angel, tree, apple, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - owl and book hanging in BR., Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing framed)
    - cherub and satyr, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - medallion, donkey reading (rep.), Tailpiece - ¼ p. (drawing missing)
    - angel in rain, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - angels, man and organ, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Monk drawing devil, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - Cont and castle, Tailpiece - ¼ page
    - Financier paying..., Tailpiece - ¼ page (drawing missing)
    - demon devil, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - devil, monk, Disputa..., Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - devil, cherub, bomb, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - owl and book (rep.), Tailpiece - ¼ p. (drawing framed)
    - medallion, donkey reading (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p. (drawing missing)
    - art exhibit, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - angels kill dragon, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - leoping leopard (rep.), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Sephyrine lamenting, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - sphinx and satyr, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - monkey ascending to Heaven, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - angels with spears (rep.), Tailpiece - 3/4 p. (drawing missing)
    - hooded judges, torturing, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - devil, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
      The Strouse Collection has a total of 25 original drawings by Frank Pape for THE REVOLT OF THE ANGELS. These include only 1 full page illustration (there are 12 in book). The double endleaves count as 4. The drawing for the half-title, and drawing for the heading are present. 18 original drawings of tailpieces are present (the book includes 28). There are no deocrated initials.
      Original drawings -
      1 full page illustration (12 in book)
      4 full page endleaves
      1 half-title
      1 heading
      18 tailpieces (28 in book)
      0 decorated initials (35 in book)
      25 original drawings
- FRANK PAPÉ ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the NORMAN H. STROUSE COLLECTION From THAIS (Box 7)
  - FRANCE, Anato IE. Thais. A Translation by Robert B. Douglas with Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. With 12 full page illustrations, 5 full page decorations preceding Parts, double-page decorated end-papers, front and back, 4 decorated tailpieces to Parts, decorated half-title, and five decorated initials preceding Parts. Black cloth binding, gilt stamped with Pape designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. (1930)
    Strouse Collection has all original drawings for this book except the 5 initials.
    - Nun and courtesan, symbols., Double, full page
    - Every night..., Full page
    - Paphnutius spoke..., Full page
    - They laughed at..., Full page
    - The Monster gently..., Full page
    - They come, the angels..., Full page
    - She let fall..., Full page
    - Therefore he conversed..., Full page
    - One day I saw..., Full page
    - A shower of stones..., Full page
    - One morning she..., Full page
    - He was about to..., Full page
    - The demons no longer..., Full page
    - Half-title ½ page
    - The Lotus - monk, angels, Thais, dragon - border, Titlepage to Part I. 3/4 p.
    - The Papyrus - child, Thais, Nubian slave, heaven., Titlepage to Part II. 3/4 p.
    - The Papyrus-Paphnutius leads Thais through desert., Titlepage to Part II (cont') 3/4 p.
    - Thais attends banquot, Titlepage to Part II. 3/4 p.
    - The Euphorbia - Thais upon her bier., Titlepage to Part III. 3/4 p.
    - 3 nymphs dancing, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - fountain, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - skull, cross, dove, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Caged bird, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - pictorially designed for head of text for each section, Initials - 5 (missing) 1 x 3/4
      The Strouse Collection has a total of 26 original Frank Pape drawings for THAIS. The only drawings not present are the five initial designs. These donot seem to be included with any of the original collections.
      5 section titles
      4 tailpieces
      26
      TOTAL 23 original drawings. The detailed description of the drawings, their frequent repetition, and the separation of the many parts, therefore does not tally with the actual count of the original drawings.
- Thai (Box 8)
- "Pestilence, War, and Famine", 1 framed drawing (Box 8)
- Unidentified (Box 8)